Smith Club of Cambridge Records, 1939-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Cambridge Records
1939-[ongoing]
Smith Club of Cambridge
RG 90 UUID:0c709ac3-af18-452c-83d7-ea3bac55f9f4
4 boxes (1 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
The Smith Club of Cambridge, Massachusetts records documents the activities of one of the oldest of the College's many community clubs. Types of material include by-laws; club procedures; correspondence; fundraising; invitations and programs; membership and officers; photographs; publicity; and planning materials from wine-tasting parties, the most popular and lucrative fundraiser of the Club. Notable correspondents include Presidents Thomas C. Mendenhall and Jill Ker Conway.
Historical Note
The Smith Club of Cambridge, one of the oldest of the College's many community clubs was started in 1922 and has several hundred members. The purpose of the Alumnae Association and all of its alumnae clubs is to "'further the well-being of the College and its graduates by increasing the interest of members in the College and in each other.'" The contribution of funds to the Smith College Scholarship Fund and to the Alumnae Fund is one of the main responsibilities of the Alumnae Clubs. In the past, the Cambridge branch has raised funds through book sales, telethons, and rummage sales. Perhaps the most popular and lucrative fundraiser is the annual wine-tasting party which has occurred each May for almost the entire history of the Club. The Cambridge Smith Club as well as clubs which represent Andover-Merrimack, Arlington-Belmont-Waltham, Boston, Concord-Lexington-Lincoln, North Shore, South Shore, Southeast, Wellesley, and Winchester are all part of the Boston League of Smith College Clubs.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Smith Club of Cambridge records consist of one linear foot of files relating to club activities. Types of material include by-laws; club procedures; correspondence; fundraising; invitations and programs; membership and officers; minutes of executive committee meetings, annual meetings, and club meetings; photographs; publicity; treasurer's reports, and planning materials from wine-tasting parties. The bulk of the material dates from 1951-1980. Notable correspondents include Presidents Thomas C. Mendenhall and Jill Ker Conway.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open to research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives.
History of the Collection
The Smith Club of Cambridge donated their records to the Smith College Archives from 1939 to 1991.
Search Terms
Smith Club of Cambridge; Smith College--Alumni and alumnae; Mendenhall, Thomas Corwin; Conway, Jill K., 1934-
Additional Information
Related Material
- 90. Alumnae Association
- By-Laws 1951-1980 Feb (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Club Procedures 1954 Oct-1962 Oct (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence 1958 Mar -1961 Oct (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence 1963 Apr-1970 Aug (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence 1971 Oct - 1975 Apr (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence 1975 May - 1977 Sep (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence 1978 Jun - 1987 Apr (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence 1999-2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Fundraising 1958 - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8-25)
- Fundraising 1976 - 1983 (Box 2, Folder 26-33)
- Invitations and Programs 1942, 1947, 1948, 1953 Apr - 1962 May (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Invitations and Program 1963 Apr - 1987 Feb (Box 2, Folder 35-37)
- Membership and Officers 1953 Nov - 1986 Jul (Box 2, Folder 38-40)
- Minutes, Newspaper clippings 1939-1947 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Minutes, Newspaper clippings 1946 -1953 (Box 3, Folder 42-43)
- Annual Meeting Minutes 1952 May - 1980 Apr (Box 3, Folder 44-46)
- Club Minutes 1953 Apr - 1986 Oct (Box 3, Folder 47-49)
- Executive Committee Minutes 1951 Jun - 1970 Jun (Box 3, Folder 50-52)
- Photographs 1964 May (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Publicity 1954 Oct - ca. 1986 (Box 3, Folder 54-55)
- Treasurer's Reports 1952 Apr - 1986 May (Box 3, Folder 56-58)
- Wine Tasting Part-Planning 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 59)